Guide to the School of Nursing, Yale University, Historical Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Photographs, miscellaneous
  - National Biennial Nursing Convention Joint Session, 1938 (Box 144, Folder 1421)
  - NINDB, 1960 (Box 144, Folder 1421)
- Policies and Objectives
  - Guide for preparation of master's thesis, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 719)
  - Guidelines, procedures, and position papers, Circa 1975-1990 (Box 58, Folder 720)
  - Philosophy and objectives, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 721)
  - Policies, Circa 1979-1990 (Box 58, Folder 722)
  - "State of the School Address," Dean Judith B. Krauss, 1985, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 723-724)
  - Yale University policies, Circa 1985-1987 (Box 58, Folder 725)
- Primary Care, "National League for Nursing Position Statement on the Education of Nurse Practitioners", Circa 1979 (Box 58, Folder 726)
- Programs, photographs
  - Adult Advanced Practice, Circa 1980s-2001 (Box 58, Folder 727-728)
  - Community Health, Circa 1955, 1970s-1980s, and undated (Box 58, Folder 729)
  - Doctoral, Circa 1994-1999 (Box 58, Folder 730-731)
  - Maternal-Newborn Nursing / Nurse Midwifery Program, Circa 1955-1994 (Box 58, Folder 732)
  - Maternal-Newborn Nursing / Nurse Midwifery Program, Circa 1955-1994 (Box 59, Folder 733)
  - Nursing Systems and Policy, Circa 1990s (Box 59, Folder 734)
  - Pediatrics, Circa 1940s-2000 (Box 59, Folder 735-738)
  - Psychiatric-Mental Health, Circa 1970s-1998 (Box 59, Folder 739)
  - Research, Circa 1980s-1990s (Box 59, Folder 740)
- Psychiatric-Mental Health, news articles, 1947-1978 (Box 59, Folder 741)
- Public health nursing
  - Committee minutes, correspondence, photographs, publications, 1918-1919, 1958, 1985, and undated (Box 59, Folder 742)
  - Winslow, C.E.A., correspondence, news, and photographs, 1927-1957, and undated (Box 59, Folder 743)
- Publicity
  - Brochures and flyers, Circa 1932-1990, and undated (Box 59, Folder 744)
  - Brochures and articles, Circa 1993-2000, and undated (Box 60, Folder 745)
  - Photographs for brochures and Bulletin, Circa 1990s (Box 142, Folder 1405)
  - Recruitment booklet pictures (negatives), Circa 1976 (Box 60, Folder 746)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital / Grace Hospital flyers, photographs, news, 1931-1950 (Box 60, Folder 747)
- Research files
  - Abramovitz, A.B., and Elaine Burnham, "Self Understanding in Professional Education: A Pilot Project in Schools of Nursing in Wisconsin", 1965 (Box 60, Folder 748)
  - Abramovitz, Mimi, and Dorothy O. Helly, "Report on a Project to Integrate Scholarship on Women into the Professional Curriculum at Hunter College", 1987 (Box 60, Folder 749)
  - Adelphi University, "PRN: The Adelphi Report," 1977-1982, Circa 1978-1982 (Box 60, Folder 750-752)
  - Allen, Moyra, "Stratification in Ward Nursing Groups: The Effects on Nursing Performance and on Patient Satisfaction," Ph.D. dissertation, 1967 (Box 60, Folder 753)
  - Altro Health and Rehabilitation Services, Inc., "Proceedings of the Institute on Rehabilitation of the Mentally Ill", 1962 (Box 60, Folder 754)
  - American Hospital Association and HRET, "Summary of Research Activities Under Way or Completed by AHA and HRET in 1972" (Box 61, Folder 755)
  - Appalachian Regional Commission, "Report of the Health Advisory Committee", 1966 (Box 61, Folder 756)
  - Argyris, Chris, "Understanding Human Behavior in Organizations: One Viewpoint," Yale University, Industrial Administration, Circa 1959 (Box 61, Folder 757)
  - Austin, Florence C., "Characteristics of Psychiatric Patients Who Utilize Public Health Nursing Services," Visiting Nurse Association, Hartford, Connecticut, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 758)
  - Ayers, Rachel, "The Clinical Nurse Specialist: An Experiment in Role Effectiveness and Role Development", 1972 (Box 61, Folder 761)
  - Bambino, Charlotte, et al., "Report of Public Health Nursing Project on Defining Clinical Content Graduate Nursing Programs," Western Interstate Commission on Higher Education, 1960 (Box 61, Folder 762)
  - Barrett, Jean, "The Nurse Specialist and Hospital Organization," final progress report, 1969-1971, Circa 1971 (Box 61, Folder 763)
  - Bellam, Gwendoline, "The Effect of Age and Severity of Illness on the Number and Type of PRN Medications Ordered for the Pediatric Patient and Their Consequent Impact on the Number and Types of Decisions to be Made by the Pediatric Nurse", Undated (Box 61, Folder 764)
  - Bircher, Andrea, "Nursing Viewpoint 1971: Phase II, Preliminary Report to Participants", 1972 (Box 61, Folder 765)
  - Bliss, Ann, et al., "The Emergency Room Nurse Orders X-Rays of Distal Limbs in Orthopaedic Trauma," Yale University School of Medicine, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 766)
  - Blumberg, Mark, "Economic Feasibility of Automating Selected Hospital Activities," Stanford Research Institute, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 767)
  - Boek, Walter, et al., "Social Class, Maternal Health and Child Care," New York State Department of Health, 1957 (Box 62, Folder 768)
  - Boston Children's Hospital, Departments of Nursing, "Professional Practice: Family Centered Pediatric Care", 1984 (Box 62, Folder 769)
  - Boston University School of Nursing
    - Research Reports
      - Number 1, Ward, Catherine, and Constance Rosenberger, "Development of a Social Adjustment Rating Scale for Hospitalized Psychiatric Patients", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 770)
      - Number 2, Spatafore, Elvira, "Development of a Tool to be Used to Test the Clustering of Disease Around Nursing Care Problems", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 771)
      - Number 3, Sawitsky, Helen M., "Self-Examination of the Breasts - A Teaching Challenge", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 772)
      - Number 4, Ferguson, Charlotte, "The Research Process: A Case History", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 773)
      - Number 5, Hargreaves, Anne, and L. Heath Marion, "A Study of the Values of Students Graduating from Boston University School of Nursing in 1962 - 1963 - 1964", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 774)
      - Number 9, Gordon, Marjory, "Nursing Knowledge of Entering Graduate Students", 1965 (Box 62, Folder 775)
    - "Summaries of Field Studies Completed in 1965" (Box 62, Folder 776)
  - British Columbia, University of, "National Conference on Research in Nursing Practice", 1971 (Box 62, Folder 777)
  - Brown, Gordon D., et al., "Methods for Hospital Service and Bed Need Assessment, A Report to Health Planners and Administrators", 1974 (Box 62, Folder 778)
  - Brown, Martha, "Effects of Skilled Nursing Care Upon Personalization of Older Patients," Final Progress Report, Washington University School of Nursing, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 779)
  - Bullock, Robert P., "What do Nurses Think of Their Profession?" Final Report to the Ohio State Nurses' Association, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 780)
  - California, University of, Center for the Health Sciences, " Conference of Principal Investigators and Project Directors - Faculty Research Development Grants", 1964 (Box 63, Folder 781)
  - Campbell, Jean, "Statement on Characteristics of Graduate Education in Nursing - Workshops," National League for Nursing, Department of Baccalaureate and Higher Degree Programs, 1964 (Box 63, Folder 782)
  - Case Western Reserve University, "Development, Implementation, and Evaluation of an Educational Program: The Role of the Professional Nurse in Primary Health Care", 1976 (Box 63, Folder 783)
  - Cavero, Carmela, et al., "The Potential Role of the Nurse-Midwife in the Provision of Maternity Care in the United States," Columbia University, thesis, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 784)
  - Chambers, Wilda G., and Geraldine G. Price, "A Survey of PRN Medication Orders Prescribed for Medical-Surgical Patients", Undated (Box 63, Folder 785)
  - Chandler, Kenneth A., "Three Aspects of Dying and Their Differential Effects on Social Behavior," Yale University, 1964 (Box 64, Folder 786)
  - Children's Hospital of Los Angeles, "Mutual Expectations for the Neophyte Staff Nurse - A Cooperative Effort of Nursing Education and Service," summary, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 787)
  - Christiansen, Marjorie M., "Utilization of Basic Science Principles in Solving Nursing Care Problems," University of Albuquerque, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 788)
  - Cohen, Eva D., "Women in Medicine: A Survey of Professional Activities, Career Interruptions and Conflict Resolutions," Yale University School of Medicine, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 789)
  - Colflesh, Virginia G., "A Survey to Assess the Ability of Nurses' Aides and Public Health Nurses to Perceive Unsafe Acts and Conditions," Pennsylvania Department of Health, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 790)
  - Colorado, University of
    - "Science and Direct Patient Care," papers presented at the Fourth Annual Nurse Scientist Conference, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 791)
    - "Science and Direct Patient Care: II," papers presented at the Fifth Annual Nurse Scientist Conference, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 792)
  - Community Health Studies Unit, "The Control of Congestive Heart Failure Through a Careful Follow-Up Program," Final Report, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 794)
  - Conant, Lucy H., "Exploratory Study of Nurse-Patient Give and Take," Terminal Progress Report, Yale University, 1967 (Box 65, Folder 795)
  - Conference on In-service Training, "Planning for Comprehensive In-service Training in a State Mental Health Program", 1963 (Box 65, Folder 796)
  - Connecticut Cancer Consortium and Capital Area Health Consortium, University of Connecticut Health Center, "Connecticut Community Based Cancer Control Program", 1977 (Box 65, Folder 797)
  - Connecticut State Department of Health
    - "Inactive Health Professionals Project, Final Report," 1968-1970, Circa 1970 (Box 65, Folder 798)
    - "Manpower Implications of the Inter-Relationship Between Social Work and Public Health Nursing Practice", 1965 (Box 65, Folder 799)
  - Cornell University, "Cornell Studies of Job Satisfaction," collection of papers, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 802)
  - Cowles, John T., and Jenny L. Csanyi, "Research Training of Medical Students: A Survey of Faculty and Students at 13 Schools with USPHS Experimental Training Grants," University of Pittsburgh, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 803)
  - Cumming, John H., "Research Training for Public Health Nurses," Final Report, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 804)
  - Cunningham, Rosella, "Team Nursing in a Generalized Public Health Nursing Program (Not Including Bedside Care)," University of Toronto, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 805)
  - Dahlin, Bernice, "Service Following Rehabilitation Training," Committee on Health, Department of Public Affairs, Community Service Society of New York, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 806)
  - Davis, Fred, "Professional Socialization as Subjective Experience: The Case of Student Nurses," International Sociological Association meetings, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 807)
  - Deutscher, Irwin, "Public Images of the Nurse, Part II of a Study of the Registered Nurse in a Metropolitan Community," Community Studies, Inc., 1955 (Box 66, Folder 808)
  - Diers, Donna, Ruth Schmidt, and Ann Hempy, "Studies in Nurse-Patient Interaction," Final Progress Report, 1965-1971, Circa 1971 (Box 67, Folder 813)
  - Disbrow, Mildred A., "Factors Involved in Successful Breast Feeding," University of California Los Angeles, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 814)
  - Donahue, Wilma, "Background Paper on Role and Training of Professional Personnel," White House Conference on Aging, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 815)
  - Dorsch, Helen, "Doctors' Expectations of Nurse Action and Judgement in the Use of PRN Pain Medication Orders", Undated (Box 67, Folder 816)
  - Elliott, Jo Eleanor, Toward More Effective Teaching in WCHEN Schools, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 820)
  - Emory University School of Nursing, "Report of Program of Home Care and Exploratory Study of Nursing and Related Needs and Wants Among Economically Independent Persons Having Chronic Health Conditions", 1965 (Box 68, Folder 823)
  - Etkin, Thomas, "An Evaluation of the Influence of Doctors on Nursing Activity Using the Critical Incident Technique," Yale University School of Medicine, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 824)
  - Evansville, University of, "Developing Teaching Techniques Designed to Improve Utilization of Knowledge from the General Education Component," Final Progress Report, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 825)
  - Fakkema, La Verne, "Professional Role Change: The Extended Nursing Role," California Department of Public Health, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 826)
  - Fallon, Elizabeth, "A Study of the Therapeutic Value of Tactile Stimulation in a Nurse-Patient Relationship," University of Pennsylvania, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 827)
  - Fasulo, Alfred, et al., "Woodbridge: A Community Diagnosis", 1976 (Box 68, Folder 828)
  - Feeney, James J., "Utilization of Medical Services by Student Nurses," Final Report, Beth Israel Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 829)
  - Feyerherm, A.M., "Measures of Hospital Patient Care Loads," Kansas State University, 1964 (Box 69, Folder 832)
  - Florida State Board of Health, "Final Report of a Study of Extrahospital Nursing Needs in a Retirement Area," 1962-1964, Circa 1964 (Box 69, Folder 835)
  - Freeman, Elaine, "The 'God Committee,'" The New York Times, 1972 (Box 69, Folder 836)
  - Freeman, Ruth, "Newer Aspects of Community Participation in the Public Health Program," lecture at Yale University School of Nursing, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 837)
  - Freund, Louis E., and Ingeborg G. Mauksch, "Optimal Nursing Assignments Based on Difficulty," University of Missouri-Columbia, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 838)
  - Ganong, Warren L., "Comparative Evaluation of Hospital Beds," Final Report, University of Pittsburgh, 1960 (Box 70, Folder 839)
  - Gibbard, Eleanor R., "Some Outcomes of Degree and Diploma Nursing Education in West Virginia", 1960 (Box 70, Folder 840)
  - Glick, Orpha J., Laura C. Dustan, and Etta H. Rasmussen, "Nursing Education in Iowa: A Study of Students and Faculty," Iowa Nurses Association and League for Nursing, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 841)
  - Goldenberg, Robert L., and Judith F. Koski, The Improved Pregnancy Outcome Project: An Analysis fo the Impact of a Federal Program on Infant Mortality, 1984 (Box 70, Folder 842)
  - Goldfarb, A.I., "Summary Report: Study of Psychological Needs of Aged Patients at Home," Vising Nurse Service of New York, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 843)
  - Gregorie, Judith, Donna Diers, and John A. Wolfer, "A Study of Some Dimensions of a Hospital Unit in Operation," Yale University School of Nursing, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 845)
  - Griffin, Gerald, Clinical Nursing Instruction by Television, Teachers College, Columbia University, and other booklets and papers, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 846)
  - Griffin, Winifred H., "Proceedings of the Second Inter-University Faculty Work Conference," Regional Nursing Program, 1960 (Box 70, Folder 847)
  - Hagen, Elizabeth, and Luverne Wolff, Nursing Leadership Behavior in General Hospitals, Teachers College, Columbia University, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 848)
  - Hallstrom, Betty J., "Nursing Diagnoses and Reporting in C & Y Projects," Minnesota Systems Research, Inc., 1972 (Box 71, Folder 851)
  - Hansen, Ann C., "Study of Essentials for Public Health Nursing Field Experience," University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1963 (Box 71, Folder 852)
  - Hansen, Ann C., et al., "Decision-Making in Public Health Nursing," University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1964 (Box 71, Folder 853)
  - Hanson, Robert C., Nurse-Patient Communication: A Manual for Public Health Nurses in Northern New Mexico, New Mexico State Department of Health, 1964 (Box 71, Folder 854)
  - Hartley, Wynona S., and Ruth Stephenson Hassanein, "Computing the Median Score from Standard TST Data," University of Kansas, Undated (Box 71, Folder 856)
  - Hassenplug, Lulu W., "Final Report: Pilot Project Mental Health Training for Public Health Nurses and School Nurses," University of California, Los Angeles, School of Nursing, 1967 (Box 71, Folder 857)
  - Hathaway, J.S., et al., "Study of the Nurse's Role in a University Health Service," National League for Nursing, Council on Occupational Health Nursing, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 861)
  - Havron, Dean, and Douglas Courtney, A Design for a Study of Nursing Care and Patient Welfare, Institute for Research in Human Relations, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 862)
  - Health Systems Agency of South Central Connecticut, Inc., "Proposed Health Systems Plan: Goals, Objectives, and Recommended Actions with Rationale", 1977 (Box 72, Folder 863)
  - Heidgerken, Loretta E., "The Graduate Curriculum Study," Catholic University of America, School of Nursing, 1962 (Box 72, Folder 864)
  - Henley, Barbara, and Milton Davis, "Satisfaction and Dissatisfaction: A Study of the Chronically Ill Aged Patient," Cornell University Medical College, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 865)
  - Holman, Barbara Lucas, "A Time Study of Nursing Activity in 'Rooming-In,'" Grace-New Haven Hospital, Undated (Box 72, Folder 866)
  - Hopkins, Lois Jones, "Self Attitudes of Hospitalized Adolescents," Case Western Reserve University, Frances Payne Bolton School of Nursing, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 867)
  - Horn, Barbara J., and Mary Ann Swain, "Development of Criterion Measures of Nursing Care," Michigan University
    - Volume I, Appendices I and II, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 868)
    - Volume II, Appendix III, 1977 (Box 73, Folder 869)
  - Hospital Services Research Center, "Final Report (Technical Version), Demonstration and Evaluation of Integrated Health Care Facilities," 1970-1972
    - Volumes I and II, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 870-871)
    - Volumes III and IV, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 872-873)
  - Hunt, Vilma, "Occupational Health Problems of Pregnant Women," Pennsylvania State University, 1975 (Box 74, Folder 876-877)
  - Iowa Mental Health Authority, The Role of the Family in Caring for the Mentally Ill and Retarded, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 878)
  - Jackson, Jay, et al., "Methods for Studying Mental Hospitals: An Annotated Bibliography," University of Oregon, Department of Sociology, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 879)
  - Jackson, Wesley C., "Some Non-Deprivation Variables Which Influence the 'Effects' of Experimental Sensory Deprivation", 1963 (Box 74, Folder 880)
  - Jantz, Richard K., et al., "Curriculum Guide: Children's Attitudes Toward the Elderly," University of Maryland, 1976 (Box 74, Folder 881)
  - Johns Hopkins School of Health Sciences, "A Feasibility Study", 1968 (Box 74, Folder 882)
  - Johnson, Karen R., and A. Taylor, "Evaluation Report: School of Nursing Outreach Program," University of Virginia, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 884)
  - Kaufmann, Margaret A., "Autonomic Responses as Related to Nursing Comfort Measures," University of California, Los Angeles, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 885)
  - Kelleher, Rita P., "Fact Finding Survey of Massachusetts Nursing Homes," Boston College of Nursing, 1963 (Box 75, Folder 886)
  - Kelly, Ruth L., "Sabbatical Leave: Survey Report, Provisions for and Usage Made of Sabbatical Leave in Baccalaureate and Graduate Schools of Nursing," Columbia University Teachers College, 1964 (Box 75, Folder 888)
  - Kemble, Elizabeth L., "Nursing Needs of Rural Ambulatory Patients," University of North Carolina, School of Nursing, Chapel Hill, 1964 (Box 75, Folder 889)
  - Kepferle, Loyd, Improving Quality Care in the Skilled Nursing Facility in the Rural Mountain West, 1979 (Box 75, Folder 890)
  - Kim, Paul K.H., S. Zafar Hasan, and Dan Egli, Mental Health Professionals Perceive Knowledge and Skills Need, 1981 (Box 75, Folder 893)
  - Kitson, Ruth A., "Farnam Operating Room Case Study", Circa 1946-1948 (Box 75, Folder 894)
  - Klaus, David, et al., "Controlling Experience to Improve Nursing Proficiency," reports 1, 2, 3, and 4, American Institutes for Research, 1966, 1968 (Box 76, Folder 895)
  - Klein, Malcolm, "Research Reports and Technical Notes," Numbers 12, 18, 29, 32, 34, 35, 45, 48, 49, and 50, Boston University Human Relations Center, 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 896)
  - Klerman, Lorraine V., and James F. Jekel, "Serving School Age Mothers," Yale University School of Medicine, Epidemiology and Public Health, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 897)
  - Kolthoff, Norma J., "Factors Affecting Circulation in Regenerated Adrenals," Frances Payne Bolton School of Nursing, Case Western Reserve University, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 898)
  - Kolthoff, Norma J., and Rosemary Rich, "Microcirculation in Human Skin," Frances Payne Bolton School of Nursing, Case Western Reserve University, 1971 (Box 76, Folder 899)
  - Kove, Michael, et al., "A Study of the Patient Population in Propietary Nursing Homes of the Bridgeport-New Haven Area," Yale University School of Medicine, 1964 (Box 76, Folder 900)
  - Lamb, Dorothy Esther, "An Observational Study of Stress in Geriatric Patients," field study, Vanderbilt University, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 901)
  - Lambertson, Eleanor, "A Project to Study the Problems and Methods Involved in Incorporating Mental Health-Psychiatric Nursing Concepts and Principles into Graduate Programs in Nursing Education," Columbia University, Teachers College, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 902)
  - Lantieri, Linda, and Rosalind Winter, "A Teaching Manual for a Special Course for Teachers and Nurses on Priorities in Parenting", 1976 (Box 77, Folder 903)
  - Larson, Leonard, "Background Paper on Health and Medical Care," White House Conference on Aging, 1961 (Box 77, Folder 904)
  - Laverty, Ruth, "The Utilization of Local Facilities in the Supervision of Psychiatric Patients, An Experimental Project," and summary, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 905)
  - LeMat, Aline F., "One Exploration into Content and Method of Public Health Nursing," Department of Public Affairs, Community Service Society of New York, 1963 (Box 77, Folder 906)
  - Leonard, Robert C., and Roslyn R. Elms, "The Effects of Varied Nursing Approaches During Effective Admission to a General Hospital," Yale University School of Nursing, 1964 (Box 77, Folder 907)
  - Leonard, Robert C., and Florence S. Wald, "Development of Patient Care Research," Yale University School of Nursing, 1969 (Box 77, Folder 908)
  - Lewinson, Peter M., Martin Shaffer, and Julian Libet, "A Behavioral Approach to Depression," University of Oregon, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 912)
  - Lewis, Charles, and B. Resnik, " The Dynamics of Nursing in Ambulatory Patient Care," Final Report, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 913)
  - Lindeman, Carol, and Sister Edith Tuberty, "Integration of Human Relations Content in Baccalaureate Nursing," College of St. Catherine, Department of Nursing, 1965 (Box 78, Folder 914)
  - Long, Ernest S., "Career Choice in Psychiatric Nursing and the Undergraduate Psychiatric Nursing Experience," Western Reserve University, 1962 (Box 78, Folder 915)
  - Lundquist, Norma, "Connecticut State Department of Health, Public Health Nursing Division, Inactive Health Professionals Project," Final Quarterly Progress Report, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 916)
  - Lutz, Evelyn M., and Jeanne S. Berthold, "Creating a Climate for Educational Technology in Nursing," Case Western Reserve University, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 917)
  - Maher, Mary, "Proceedings of the First Inter-University Faculty Work Conference," Stowe, Vermont, Regional Nursing Program, 1960 (Box 78, Folder 918)
  - Mahl, George, "The Patient's Language is Expressive Behavior," Progress Report, Yale University, 1961 (Box 78, Folder 919)
  - Maryland, University of, School of Nursing, Research Development Project, "Priorities and Problems in Nursing Research", 1971 (Box 79, Folder 920)
  - Mauksch, Hans O., "The Nurse: A Study in Self and Role Perception," Illinois Institute of Technology, Undated (Box 79, Folder 921)
  - McBride, Angela, "The Effects of Varied Nursing Approaches on Pain: A Clinical Experiment", Undated (Box 79, Folder 922)
  - McGuigan, F.J., "Covert Language Behavior and Auditory Hallucinations," Hollins College, 1965 (Box 79, Folder 923)
  - McKenna, J.V., "The Service Manager System: Nurse Efficacy and Cost," Research Proposal, Barnes Hospital, St. Louis, Missouri, 1965 (Box 79, Folder 924)